<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zac Heisey | Digital Marketing Consulting for Nonprofits</title>
    <description>I'm a Digital Marketing Specialist living in Baltimore, MD. I help nonprofits build &amp; optimize online campaigns and establish a strong digital presence.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 13:30:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 13:30:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rockhaven Ministry Notes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Currently on WordPress &amp;gt; Are they looking to redesign site? If so, why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Homepage design and content could be adjusted to better communicate Rockhaven’s mission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Main nav bar needs to be redesigned so that it doesn’t distract from the content of the page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the main goals of the website? Drive donations? Attract more volunteers? Whatever it is, the layout, design, and CTAs should reflect those goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO/Marketing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technical SEO needs a lot of help:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Need to implement Google Analytics
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Need to utilize Yoast SEO plugin (already installed?) to optimize title tags, meta descriptions, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are some terms that people might use to discover your organization online?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;refugee assistance&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;help refugees&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;refugees in &lt;em&gt;__&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dedicated budget for online marketing efforts?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the capacity to create quality content on an ongoing basis?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider applying for Google Ad Grants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Potential partnerships that could be used to leverage online presence?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there specific fundraising efforts, annual events, etc. that could benefit from concentrated, short-term marketing efforts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Media:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FB &amp;amp; Twitter engagement are low and outdated &amp;gt; Need to pick this up significantly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which channels should they focus on? FB and Twitter are likely the best options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider running paid social media ads on FB &amp;amp; Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/catchafire/rockhaven-ministry-notes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/catchafire/rockhaven-ministry-notes/</guid>
        
        
        <category>catchafire</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Dimensions Tab: AdWords' Hidden Treasure</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are dozens of places in your AdWords account from which you can pull meaningful, actionable insights. The options available for you to slice and dice your paid search data are numerous - so much so that it can be difficult to know where to look first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first places I look when I take over a new AdWords account, or I’m trying to optimize a campaign for an existing client, is the &lt;strong&gt;Dimensions tab&lt;/strong&gt;. This section of your AdWords account can provide some crazy useful information about your PPC performance that you can’t really access in other parts of your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[INCLUDE SCREENSHOT OF DIMENSIONS TAB HERE]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below I’ll walk you through some of the different types of data (aka “Views”) you can access in the Dimensions tab, why it’s awesome, and how you can use this information to increase your PPC performance and reach your marketing goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Time view is perfect if you’re trying to understand exactly when people are (and are not) engaging with your ads. The Time view actually consists of several “sub-views,” which show performance based on the date, day of the week, quarter, or even down to the hour of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[INCLUDE SCREENSHOT OF TIME VIEW HERE]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My go-to view here is &lt;em&gt;Day of the Week&lt;/em&gt;, as it gives me a starting point to understand user behavior based on time (which I can then explore deeper in the &lt;em&gt;Hour of Day&lt;/em&gt; view.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also helps me pinpoint on which days I should increase/decrease bids and budgets and which I should pause altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;urls&quot;&gt;URLs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice there are two URL-related view options under the Dimensions tab: &lt;em&gt;Destination URL&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Final URL&lt;/em&gt;. Both of these views give you the same information: which of your landing page URLs are is performing best in terms of clicks, impressions, CTR, conversions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a good idea to cross-reference this data with on-page stats for these pages in your Google Analytics account, paying close attention to bounce rate, pages per session, average session duration, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason there are two views providing basically the same data is that Google has been working to replace Destination URLs with Final URLs as part of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/adwords/answer/6049217?hl=en&amp;amp;authuser=0&quot;&gt;upgrade process&lt;/a&gt; intended to make ad creation and tracking updated much easier for AdWords users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[INCLUDE SCREENSHOT OF FINAL URL VIEW HERE]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, you’ll start seeing less and less data in the &lt;em&gt;Destination URL&lt;/em&gt; view as Google works to phase it out, so stick with the &lt;em&gt;Final URL&lt;/em&gt; view for review and reporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keywords&quot;&gt;Keywords&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords are at the center of search engine marketing and represent the driving force behind most AdWords campaigns. Unless you’re using Exact match keywords exclusively in your campaigns, or your negative keywords lists are more exhaustive than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WhfK98f5S00&quot;&gt;Bubba’s shrimp preparation list&lt;/a&gt;, periodically checking the &lt;em&gt;Search terms&lt;/em&gt; view is a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than viewing the aggregate performance data for the keywords you’re explicitly bidding on, the &lt;em&gt;Search terms&lt;/em&gt; view shows you the &lt;strong&gt;specific search terms that users typed into Google which led to impressions and/or clicks for your ads&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, if you’re bidding on the Phrase match keyword “blue socks,” the &lt;em&gt;Search terms&lt;/em&gt; view will show individual data for all user search queries that triggered impressions/clicks for that keyword. So you might see performance data for search terms like “buy blue socks,” “blue socks for sale,” “shop blue socks online,” “blue socks sizes,” etc. This data can serve as a valuable resource when it comes to keyword expansion or building out your negative keyword lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[INCLUDE SCREENSHOT OF SEARCH TERMS VIEW HERE]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other keyword-centric view in the Dimensions tab is the &lt;em&gt;Paid &amp;amp; Organic&lt;/em&gt; view, which allows you to compare organic and paid performance for the same queries, as well as check out the impact on performance when your website shows in &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; the paid and organic listings for a given search query. Understanding this information is important for a few reasons: first, it helps you see exactly how your organic and paid search efforts are working together. Second, it can reveal new keyword targeting opportunities in AdWords, as well as optimization and content creation opportunities on the organic front. Finally, reviewing the data in the &lt;em&gt;Paid &amp;amp; Organic&lt;/em&gt; view allows you to utilize your online marketing budget more efficiently across your organic and paid search efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[INCLUDE SCREENSHOT OF PAID &amp;amp; ORGANIC VIEW HERE]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to get data populating in the &lt;em&gt;Paid &amp;amp; Organic&lt;/em&gt; view, you’ll need to have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/home&quot;&gt;Search Console&lt;/a&gt; account set up for your website, and have that account linked to your AdWords account. You can learn how to do that, and read more about the &lt;em&gt;Paid &amp;amp; Organic&lt;/em&gt; view &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/adwords/answer/3097241?hl=en&amp;amp;authuser=0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;location-info&quot;&gt;Location Info&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three different views in the Dimenions tab that focus on location information pertaining to your campaigns: &lt;em&gt;Geographic&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;User Location&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Distance&lt;/em&gt;. I’ll break down each one below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographic&lt;/strong&gt;: According to Google, this view “shows your customers’ physical locations, or locations that they had shown interest in through searches or content they had viewed.” You’ll want to reference this view if your campaign’s location target settings are set to the default: &lt;em&gt;People in, searching for, or who show interest in my targeted location&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Location&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;em&gt;User Location&lt;/em&gt; view “shows only your customers’ physical locations, regardless of any locations they may have shown interest in.” If your campaign’s location target is set to &lt;em&gt;People in my targeted location&lt;/em&gt;, this view will be especially useful for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distance&lt;/strong&gt;: Lastly, the &lt;em&gt;Distance&lt;/em&gt; view shows performance data organized by distance from the address listed in your &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/adwords/answer/2404182?hl=en&quot;&gt;Location Extension&lt;/a&gt;. This information can be helpful in determine bid adjustments based on radius targeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[INCLUDE SCREENSHOT OF USER LOCATION VIEW HERE]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;call-details&quot;&gt;Call Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we have the &lt;em&gt;Call Details&lt;/em&gt; view. In order to use this view, you’ll need to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/adwords/answer/2453991?hl=en&quot;&gt;Call Extensions&lt;/a&gt; enabled. The &lt;em&gt;Call Details&lt;/em&gt; view provides some useful insights into phone calls generated by your AdWords ads via Call Extensions. Call start and end times, whether the call was received or missed, the duration of the call in seconds, the caller’s area code, the call type (“mobile click-to-call” or “manually dialed”), and call source (“ad” or “website”) is all captured in this view. Definitely a great resource if your organization considers phone calls a valuable KPI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[INCLUDE SCREENSHOT OF CALL DETAILS VIEW HERE]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dimensions tab sections outlined above are the ones that I find myself using most often. There are some additional sections in the tab (Labels, Top Movers, Free Clicks, Campaign / Ad Group details, etc.) that I don’t use very much, but still might have value depending on your marketing goals and AdWords account setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend some time exploring the Dimensions tab in your AdWords account. My guess is you’ll find some useful, actionable info in there that you otherwise would have missed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 07:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/adwords-dimensions-tab-insights/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/adwords-dimensions-tab-insights/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It's 2016: Are We Doing Real Company Sh*t Yet?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hopefully by now, every SEO and digital marketing professional has seen Wil Reynolds’ MozCon 2012 presentation on ‘&lt;strong&gt;Real Company Shit (RCS)&lt;/strong&gt;’ (If not, I’ve included it below. Stop reading and watch it. All of it.). Roughly 4 years later, I still find myself wondering if our industry has matured enough to finally accept the RCS principles that Wil talks about. Based on my own experience, I’d say we’re about half way there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[EMBED MOZCON PREZ HERE] https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q-Y8xe4e9KY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got into digital marketing in 2007, SEO as an established practice was still relatively young. As a result, it was pretty much open season in terms of things you could do to get a site to rank well. We built private blog networks. We stuffed keywords in alt tags. We wrote white text on white backgrounds. We bought links from places like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalpoint.com/&quot;&gt;Digital Point&lt;/a&gt;. We paid pennies on the dollar for poorly written content and thousands of fake social followers - all in the name of improving our search engine rankings as quickly as possible. While it worked pretty well back then (and sometimes still works today), all of this stuff (according to Wil) is ‘&lt;strong&gt;fake company shit (FCS)&lt;/strong&gt;.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where are we today? On one hand, I do think we’re making strides towards RCS as &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; way to do digital marketing. Thanks to a multitude of &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/google-algorithm-change&quot;&gt;algorithm updates&lt;/a&gt; rolled out by Google over the last few years, there’s been a shift towards creating quality content that’s actually written for &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; - not search search engines. In fact, content creation (and content marketing) has become essential to an effective digital marketing strategy. More encouraging than that, the metrics we’re using to determine success are &lt;a href=&quot;http://contentmarketinginstitute.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/2016_B2B_Report_Final.pdf&quot;&gt;skewing heavily&lt;/a&gt; towards lead quality, sales, conversion rates, and website traffic (i.e. RCS), rather than PageRank and link juice (i.e. FCS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[WTF IS JUICE IMAGE HERE]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.best-marketing.eu/dove-ad-makeover-case-study/&quot;&gt;Dove&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://linkhumans.com/case-study/red-bull&quot;&gt;Redbull&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://digiday.com/brands/inside-patagonias-content-machine/&quot;&gt;Patagonia&lt;/a&gt; are using RCS to build their brands online, and it’s earning them a ton of traffic, links, social followers, and ultimately, more business. They’re engaging their customer base by producing top-notch content that people naturally want to link to and share. You think the marketing teams for these brands are mulling over PageRank and backlink profiles? Nah, don’t think so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, however, we still have this type of crap happening:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[COMMENTS SCREENSHOT HERE]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a portion of the comments from a blog post written earlier this year that talked about scalable link building tactics. Really guys!? PBNs? Buying links from some dude in the Philippines? The biggest issue is that the post was written by pretty well-known SEO, and featured on his company’s blog - a company that sells SEO tools!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[COME ON MAN GIF HERE]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, you can still &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalpoint.com/search/30787838/?q=links+for+sale&amp;amp;o=date&quot;&gt;buy links on Digital Point&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.superspunarticle.com/&quot;&gt;article spinning&lt;/a&gt; is still a thing, you can still get &lt;a href=&quot;http://fastfollowme.com/buy-twitter-followers-40&quot;&gt;1,000 twitter followers for $5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we fix this? How can we convince our clients and our bosses that investing in RCS is the way to go, especially when there are still “experts” out there giving shitty advice and still getting results (that last part’s on you, Google)? I think it comes down to two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doing-a-better-job-of-educating-decision-makers&quot;&gt;1) Doing a Better Job of Educating Decision Makers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part can be really difficult. Mr. Client or Ms. CEO see their competitors doing spammy stuff and getting rankings, links, etc., yet you’re over here telling them they have to do it the hard way. Trust me, I feel your pain. But the more we can educate folks about the value of doing RCS - and more importantly - why digital marketers should be leading those types of initiatives, the better off our industry as a whole is going to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doing-a-better-job-of-communicating-the-value-of-our-work&quot;&gt;2) Doing a Better Job of Communicating the Value of Our Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital marketers and SEOs, whatever you do, please - FOR THE LOVE OF GOD - stop telling decisions makers about search volume and PageRank and Quality Scores and Klout Scores and all that other bullshit they don’t care about. Instead, try talking to them about revenue, brand awareness, and publicity. I mean, these are the things we’re &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be affecting through all of our hard work, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave you with this short video of Wil giving us a nice overview of what RCS means in the context of his own company, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seerinteractive.com/&quot;&gt;SEER Interactive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[RCS SEER VIDEO HERE] https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u2Z8w8bATy8&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 21:25:22 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/its-2016-are-we-doing-real-company-shit-yet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/its-2016-are-we-doing-real-company-shit-yet/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
